I'll bet this ring on our next game!
（氷室(ひむろ)）
次の試合 このリングを賭けろ！
今日の試合は
どっちにしろ 引き分けだ
Today's game is a tie.
If you lose the next game, we'll pretend this ring never existed.
もし 次の試合
タイガが負けるようなら—
このリングのことは
なかったことにしろ
（火神(かがみ)）待たせたな
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Don't hold back, Tatsuya!
（火神）
遠慮なくやろうぜ タツヤ！
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: sangofe
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: AMS, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Episode
It's Obvious
That promise you made over your ring...
（紫原(むらさきばら)）そのリングの約束さ
（氷室）ん？
It's not a bet at all.
（紫原）賭けになってないよね
どっちが勝っても 結局
兄弟やめるってことじゃん
No matter who wins, you won't be brothers anymore.
（氷室）そんな話したっけ？
（紫原）ストバスの帰り
Did I tell you about that?
On the way home from street ball.
You're not fooling anyone.
（紫原）ごまかせてないよ
（氷室）フッ…
That's right.
そうだよ
（氷室）オレは タイガと
兄弟であることをやめたいんだ
I don't want to be Taiga's brother anymore.
（青峰(あおみね)）相当やんぞ あの12番
No. 12 is pretty good.
What?
（さつき）彼に関しては—
Since this is his first appearance at a tournament,
今大会が初出場で
データがほとんどない
I don't have any data on him.
Is he really good enough to put Dai on guard at a glance?
けど 大(だい)ちゃんが一目で
警戒するほどなの？
A shot?
（火神）シュート！？
A fake?
（火神）フェイク！？
（青峰）途中まで 動きも気迫も
完全にシュートにしか見えなかった
It totally looked like he was shooting.
あんな完璧なフェイクは
初めて見たぜ
I've never seen such a perfect fake.
No, you don't!
（日向(ひゅうが)）させるか！
It's a pincer attack!
（火神）はさみうちだっ！
（氷室）はっ…
（伊月(いづき)）ああ…
（木吉(きよし)･水戸部(みとべ)）ああ…
（黒子(くろこ)）ああ…
He made the shot!
（観客１）決まったあ！
His play's so fine, I can't help but be blown away!
（観客２）鮮やかすぎて
思わず見とれちまった
（降旗(ふりはた)）キャプテンも火神も
まったく反応できないなんて…
I can't believe the captain and Kagami couldn't react at all.
What kind of trick is he using?
（福田(ふくだ)）
いったい どんなトリックが！？
He's not doing anything.
（リコ）何もしてないわ
（河原(かわはら)･福田･降旗）え？
What?
He simply stopped and made a jump shot.
（リコ）要はストップし—
ジャンプシュートをしただけ
ただ…
However, because he transitioned so smoothly,
そのつなぎが あまりにも
スムーズだったから—
neither of them noticed him enter his shooting motion.
２人とも シュートモーションに
入ったことに気付かなかったのよ
どれも
ごく普通のプレーだけど—
It's an incredibly ordinary play,
but each element is of the highest quality.
一つ一つのクオリティが
この上なく高い
He's the exact opposite of the formless Aomine.
彼は いわば—
型にはまらない
青峰君とは対極
He adheres strictly to orthodox methods.
基本に忠実な
超正統派
It's like a refined dance.
まるで流麗なダンスだわ
I saw what was happening, but couldn't respond.
（火神）見えてたのに
反応できなかった
I can't believe how smoothly he moves.
なんて 滑らかさだ
っしゃあ！
All right!
Your mind must be cold, and your heart must be hot.
（氷室）
頭は冷静に 心は熱く
そういうとこは相変わらずかよ
That part of you hasn't changed at all.
（氷室）まだだな
（火神）ん？
You still do, don't you?
Somewhere in your heart,
（氷室）
オマエ まだ心のどこかで—
you still think of me as your brother, don't you?
オレを兄として—
見ているんじゃ
ないだろうな？
（氷室）子どもの頃は—
When we were younger,
I didn't feel anything because of the obvious difference in our abilities.
明らかに実力差があって
何も感じなかった
But when I saw he was nearly as good as I was in middle school,
だが 中学の頃には—
オレと肩を並べるまでに
なった あいつを見て—
確信してしまったんだ
I realized something.
I didn't want to lose to him.
あいつにだけは負けたくない
Our relationship as brothers was getting in our way.
だから兄弟という枷(かせ)が
邪魔だったんだよ
特に あいつは
本気でやっているつもりでも—
Even if he thinks he's trying his best,
subconsciously, he holds himself back.
無意識に
セーブが かかってしまう
オレは 本気のタイガと戦いたい
I want to fight Taiga at his strongest
そして たたきつぶしたいんだよ
and crush him.
It's not a fake this time.
（火神）今度はフェイクじゃない
ブロック！
Block!
（火神）えいっ
ミラージュシュート
Mirage Shot.
That's impossible.
（日向）あり得ねぇ…
ボールがブロックをすり抜けた
The ball passed through his block.
This happened when we played street ball.
（火神）
これは… ストバスのときと同じ
You and I are enemies.
（氷室）オレとオマエは敵同士
（火神）あっ…
もっと殺す気でこいよ
Come at me like you're trying to kill me.
Kagami!
（土田(つちだ)）火神！
（火神）えっ オレ！？
Me?
Should we be doing this?
（伊月）いいのか？
She's probably giving him time to cool his head.
（木吉）たぶん
頭を冷やす時間を作るためだ
勝負と情を分けきれないのが
火神の悪いとこだな
Kagami's weakness is he can't separate his emotions from the game.
He's too kind.
あいつは優しすぎる
We can't afford to worry about him though.
けど 人の心配ばかり
してらんないぜ
We've got a much bigger problem.
こっちのほうが よっぽど難問だ
We need to score two points off Yosen.
陽泉(ようせん)から２点取ること
すなわち…
In other words,
イージスの盾破りだ
we have to pierce the Shield of Aegis.
分かってんな 木吉
最初の一発が すべてだぞ
You know, everything's riding on that first shot, Kiyoshi.
I know. Honestly, it's not my specialty,
but I'll definitely make it.
（木吉）分かってる
正直 専門外だが絶対決めるさ
You never learn.
（紫原）懲りないね ホント
（木吉）ええ？
I just don't understand why people work so hard when they can't win.
やっぱり理解できないな
勝てないのに
努力する人間の気持ちは
Whether or not I can win doesn't matter.
勝てるかどうかなんて関係ない
Working towards a goal is just so much fun, I can't help myself.
目標に向かって
努力することなんて—
楽しくてしょうがないさ
オマエは楽しくないのか？ バスケ
Don't you enjoy basketball?
What?
（木吉）くっ
（紫原）ええいっ
It's annoying that you can say things like that.
（紫原）そういうこと平気で言って
ウザいんだよ オマエも黒(くろ)ちんも
Both you and Kuro-chin.
（木吉）うっ
（降旗）ダブルクラッチ！
A double clutch!
Don't act like you've accomplished anything when you're only going to lose!
（紫原）
どうせ負けるのに—
小物が充実した気分に
なってんじゃねーよ！
あっ まだだ！
It's not over yet!
（伊月）うっ… フン！
（木吉）うっ
What? When did he get there?
（福井(ふくい)）なっ！？ いつの間に！
You know, everything's riding on that first shot.
（日向）分かってんな
最初の一発が すべてだぞ
The center's shooting a three?
（氷室）
センターの彼が スリー！？
All right, Kiyoshi!
（部員たち）よっしゃー
（小金井(こがねい)）やったー！ 木吉
ハァ… てゆーか マグレでしょ？
It must've been a fluke.
（岡村(おかむら)）データにも
木吉のスリーなどない
According to our data, Kiyoshi doesn't shoot threes.
とても あとが続くとは思えん
There's no way he can keep it up.
（福井）奇策にすら なってねーよ
It's not even a clever plan.
（ホイッスル）
（陽泉部員１）よっしゃー
All right!
Nice shot!
（陽泉部員２）ナイッシュー！
Damn it.
（土田）くそっ
（木吉）気にするな こっからだ
Don't worry about it.
We're just getting started.
（伊月）うん
（日向）ああ 伏線はここまでだ
We've set the stage well enough now.
Let's go pierce the Shield of Aegis.
行くぞ
イージスの盾破り！
（福井）何だ そりゃ！？
What is this?
Well then, let's go have some fun.
（木吉）
んじゃ まっ 楽しんでこーぜ
This guy's the point guard?
（福井）
こいつがポイントガード！？
（岡村）
ううっ… どういうつもりじゃ
What do they think they're doing?
It's on you, Teppei.
（リコ）頼んだわよ… 鉄平(てっぺい)
（福井）まさか またスリーか？
Is he really going to shoot another three?
Crap, I can't get high enough!
（福井）ヤベェ 届かねぇ！
Everything you do is so annoying,
やることが
いちいちウザいんだよ
木吉！！
Kiyoshi!
（青峰）
フッ そういうことか…
So that's how it is.
Seirin's going to win this battle.
（青峰）この攻めは 誠凛(せいりん)の勝ちだ
All right!
（伊月）よしっ
（福井）何？
What?!
（劉(リュウ)）ううっ…
（紫原）うっ！
（降旗）うわぁ
（福田）紫原も追いついてきた！
Murasakibara's following!
（リコ）大丈夫よ
（福田）え？
It's all right.
What?
（リコ）こういう状況でこそ
真価を発揮するわ
His Eagle Eye is truly useful in situations like these.
彼のイーグルアイは…
Repeated attacks can't beat Murasakibara's defense.
（青峰）紫原のディフェンスは
どんな連続攻撃でも崩せねぇ
With those reflexes and his huge body,
（青峰）なぜなら
反射神経プラス あのガタイで—
he can reach most shots without jumping.
たいがいのシュートは
ほとんど跳ばずに届くからだ
However, even Murasakibara has to jump to stop
だが 木吉の
中･長距離シュートには—
紫原でも跳ばなければ届かない
Kiyoshi's mid and long-range shots.
If he jumps, his next move is delayed by the time it takes for him to land.
跳べば着地するまで
ワンテンポ 次への動作が遅れる
He can't stop attacks like that, even if he knows they're coming.
そこを突いた連続攻撃には
分かっていても追いつけない
I said it doesn't matter if I win, but don't get the wrong idea.
（木吉）勝てるかどうか
関係ないと言ったが—
勘違いするなよ
I don't intend to lose either!
負けるつもりも毛頭ない！
うらあ！
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
That formation...
（さつき）あの陣形—
また同じ作戦で
しかけるつもりなの？
Are they using the same plan again?
But isn't that...
でも あれって…
（木吉）えい
I just shouldn't jump.
（紫原）
要は 跳ばなきゃいいんでしょ
えいっ
（木吉）オマエは
好きじゃないのか？ バスケ
Don't you enjoy basketball?
（紫原）くっ ええい
Atsushi!
敦(あつし)！
What am I doing?
（紫原）何やってんだ オレは
これじゃさっきと同じ…
I'm doing the same thing as before!
（伊月）うっ
（劉･岡村）ええいっ
（伊月）フン！
（劉･岡村）うっ！
All right!
よし！ こっちも風通しが
よくなってきた！
Things are starting to flow well here too!
えいっ！
He made it! Nice three!
（福田）決まった スリー！
（小金井）これで一桁差だ！
We've cut it down to a one-digit lead!
Seirin
Yosen
（紫原）くうっ…
（ブザー）
（審判）白 タイムアウトです
White, time out!
A time out, huh?
（青峰）タイムアウトか
さすがに想定外だったみてえだな
Looks like they weren't expecting that.
木吉さんの 長距離シュートの
確率を考えれば—
Considering Kiyoshi's long-range shooting percentage,
Muk doesn't need to jump.
ムッ君
無理して跳ぶ必要ないのに…
That's why they set the stage for this first though.
そうさせないために—
伏線 はってんだろ
（さつき）え？
The first thing they did was the three he made earlier.
（青峰）１つ目は直前のスリー
Making that made a huge difference.
あれを一発で決めたのは でけえ
確率の悪さを知ってても—
Even if his percentage is low,
“また入るかも”と思わせるには
十分なインパクトだった
making them think he might make another had a big enough impact.
On top of that, Kiyoshi's has his Right of Postponement.
しかも木吉には—
“後出しの権利”ってのが
あんだろうが
シュートに行くときも
フェイクじゃなく—
When he goes for a shot,
he's really trying to make it at first instead of faking.
途中まで 本気で打ちにいってる
The last part of it is only a guess,
もう１つは
推測でしかねえけど—
but I think he pissed Murasakibara off.
紫原を挑発して怒らせたんだろ
（さつき）え？
What?
I don't know what he said,
何を言ったかは知んねえが—
but he doesn't like those kinds of guys in the first place anyway.
まっ 元から ああいうタイプは
嫌いだしな あいつは
The stage they set is moving Murasakibara's body.
そういう伏線が
紫原の体をとっさに動かしちまう
自分が嫌われてることまで
作戦に組みこんじまうんだから—
He's even using his own hatred against him.
He looks nice, but he's tough.
人のよさそうな顔して
したたかもいいとこだ
Kiyoshi, here's a towel.
（福田）木吉先輩 タオルです
（木吉）おう サンキュ
Thanks.
（木吉）ハァ… ハァ…
He's sweating so much.
（火神）すげえ汗… 当たり前だ
Of course he is.
オフェンスではポイントガード
ディフェンスではセンター
He's the point guard on offense and the center on defense.
一人二役こなしてるようなもんだ
それだけ木吉先輩は…
It's like doing two jobs at once.
Kiyoshi's just that...
（火神）黒子 頼みがあるんだ
（黒子）ん？
Kuroko, I need a favor.
（火神）
これ 捨ててきてくれねえか
Could you go throw this out?
What?
Are you sure?
いいんですか？
氷室さんとの大切な思い出の…
I thought this was an important memento.
It's fine.
（火神）いいんだ 持ってても
オレには未練でしかねぇ
Keeping it only makes it harder to let go.
Besides, between my past with Tatsuya and my future with you,
それにタツヤとの過去と
オマエらとの未来じゃ—
どっちが大切かなんて
決まってらぁ
it's obvious which is more important.
（観客たちの歓声）
（青峰）おっ 出てきたな
He's coming out.
Kagami...
（降旗）火神！
（福田）頼む！
Please.
It's okay.
（黒子）大丈夫です
（部員たち）えっ？
火神君は もう誰にも負けません
No one can beat Kagami now.
（福井）えいっ
（火神）ハァ…
A shot?
（小金井）シュート！？
（火神）え？
（日向）
なっ！ これもフェイク！？
Is this a fake too?
（火神）でえい！
（氷室）うわっ
Impossible!
（氷室）バカな！
He reached me with that form and from that distance?
あの体勢と距離から届いただと！？
The real battle's just starting, Himuro!
こっからが本当の勝負だ！
氷室！！
（氷室）でえいっ
（伊月）ううっ
（火神）伊月先輩！
（伊月）火神！
Izuki!
Kagami!
（火神）くうっっ
（部員たち）いけー！ 火神ぃぃ
Go, Kagami!
I'll crush you this time,
今度こそ ひねり潰してやるよ
Kagami!
火神！！
What should I do? Should I keep going, or...
（火神）どうする このままいくか
それとも…
…って 何考えてんだ オレは
What am I thinking?
んなもん 答えは決まってんだろ
The answer's obvious.
If I turn back now, I'm no ace!
ここで引いたらエースじゃねぇ！！
Murasakibara!
（火神）紫原！！
Go, Kagami!
（選手たち）行けぇ！火神！！
Kagami!
火神君！！
So high.
（紫原）高い…
だが それだけで
勝てると思ってんなら…
But if that's all you think it takes to win...
Don't get ahead of yourself!
調子に のってんじゃねーよ！！
Kagami!
（日向）火神！ 火神 大丈夫か？
Kagami, are you all right?
んっ すんません 大丈夫ス
Sorry.
I'm fine.
What was that?
（紫原）何だ 今のは
確かに何かをやろうとしてた
He was trying to do something.
あれは いったい？
What was that?
Kiyoshi!
（伊月）木吉！
（土田）なっ！
木吉にトリプルチーム！？
They're triple-teaming Kiyoshi?
Yosen's finally going for the big play!
（小金井）陽泉も
ついに賭けてきやがった！
（木吉）うっ ハァ ハァ…
（岡村）ええいっ
Crap!
（木吉）しまった！
Fast break!
速攻！
Himuro!
（小金井）氷室！
（火神）いかせるか 氷室！！
You're not going anywhere, Himuro!
A Mirage Shot!
（火神）ミラージュシュートか！？
（火神）なっ…
くそっ こんなときに汗で…
Damn it, slipping on sweat at a time like this.
（火神）ダメだ
このタイミングじゃ間に合わ…
It's no use!
I won't make it in time!
Kagami finally stopped Himuro's Mirage Shot!
ついに火神が氷室を止めた！
No, I just happened to slip.
（火神）
違う 今のは偶然滑って—
はっ！ そうか もしかしたら…
I see. Maybe...
Kiyoshi!
（伊月）木吉！
（木吉）ハァ ハァ…
（木吉）うっ えいっ
They're not open.
（伊月）
ダメだ オレが打つしかない！
I have to take the shot.
（伊月）えいっ
（小金井）スリー！？
A three?
You're rushing too much.
焦り過ぎでしょ もーらい
That's mine.
（木吉）ええい
（紫原）うっ
Kiyoshi!
（紫原）木吉…！
Kiyoshi's amazing!
（小金井）すげえよ 木吉！
（黒子）先輩！
（日向）木吉！
Senpai!
Kiyoshi!
（火神）木吉先輩！
（ホイッスル）
（審判）レフェリータイム！
Referee time out!
ハァ ハァ… すまん 黒子
Sorry, Kuroko.
ちょっと つまずいて
派手に転んじまっただけだ
I just tripped and fell dramatically.
ハァ… 心配するな ああ…
Don't worry about me.
Teppei, are you really...?
鉄平！ あなた ホントに…
I'm fine. Let me play.
大丈夫だ やらせてくれ 頼む
Please.
Seirin
Yosen
ハァ… やっとここまで
追い上げてきたんだ
Seirin
Yosen
We've finally made a dent.
Seirin
Yosen
I don't want to interrupt this flow.
今の流れを途切れさせたくない
まだまだやれるさ
勝とうぜ みんなで
I can keep playing.
Let's all win together!
（木吉）ハァ… ハァ…
（岡村）んんっ！
Even if I told him to stop, he wouldn't listen.
（日向）どうせ下がれっつっても
聞かねえんだろ？
だったら せめて—
In that case,
at the very least, we can try to take some pressure off him on defense.
ディフェンスの負担でも
何でもいいから…
（日向）うらぁ！
（福井）しまった スティール！！
Damn it, a steal!
They're triple-teaming him again!
（河原）またトリプルチーム！！
（降旗）３人同時攻撃！？
A three-man attack?!
What? You think you can take me?
（紫原）はぁ？ ナメてんの？
オマエら程度
まとめて ひねり潰してやるよ
I'll crush you all at once.
（伊月）えいっ
（紫原）リズムが乱れてる上に
フォームが いつもより傾いている
His rhythm and form are off.
He won't make this one.
これは入らない
This bastard. Is he using all his strength to slow me down?
（紫原）こいつ… オレを一瞬
足止めするためだけに全力を？
（紫原）くううっ！
（火神）えい！
うおおおっ！ うりゃああ！
He made it!
（ホイッスル）
（小金井）決まった〜！
We're only five points behind now!
（土田）これで点差は５点！
（火神･木吉）ううっ フンッ！
Go! Keep it up!
（小金井）いけ〜！
そのままいっちゃえ〜！
You can do it!
（黒子）
頑張れ 頑張れ みんな！
You can do it, guys!
Don't you enjoy basketball?
（木吉）
オマエは楽しくないのか？ バスケ
（紫原）だったら教えてやるよ
I'll show you just how cruel a sport basketball is.
バスケが どんだけ
残酷なスポーツかってことを
I can't take it anymore.
（紫原）
あ〜 もう これ以上 無理だわ
It's so disgusting I could puke.
（紫原）不愉快すぎて吐きそうだ
（伊月）う…
（紫原）オマエらみたいなのが
うごめいているのは…
Watching you squirm, that is.
（日向）これを止めんのかよ！？
How are we supposed to stop this?
Hard work, determination, faith...
（紫原）
努力だの 根性だの 信念だの…
He's coming.
（火神）来やがった…
（紫原）ひねり潰してやるよ
I'll crush them all.
すべて
All of them.
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
Yes! That's my Tatsuya!
You're playing quicker and faster than before!
Woof.
What? He gets in the offense as well?
Woof, woof, woof, woof-woof.
Episode
I Don't Want to Lose!
It seems this game is not over yet.
Keep holding on, Taiga.
Woof!